4. Modes of colours. 

Those of colours are also very various: some we take notice of as the different degrees, or as they were termed shades, of the same colour. 

But since we very seldom make assemblages of colours, either for use or delight, but figure is taken in also, and has its part in it, as in painting, weaving, needleworks, &c.;

those which are taken notice of do most commonly belong to mixed modes, as being made up of ideas of divers kinds, viz. figure and colour, such as beauty, rainbow, &c.